(淋浴运行)
[shower running]
[淋浴时吹口哨]
[whistling in shower]
哦!
Oh!
你好,鲁迪。
Hello, Rudy.
通常我会搜身看看你有没有打包行李。
Normally I'd frisk you to make sure you're not packing.
但在这种情况下，我破例一次。
But in this case, I'll make an exception.
你知道我是谁吗?
Do you know who I am?
Nicoletto。
Al Nicoletto.
这是一家不错的酒店。
It's a nice hotel.
我在95年杀了一个人?
I killed a guy here in ninety...five?
九十-九十六吗?
Ninety--ninety-six?
九十六年。记忆。
Ninety-six. Memories.
我没有钱。
I don't have the money.
我对天发誓。
I swear to God.
我们然后我就放你走，好吗?
We'll then I'll just  let you go, right?
向上帝发誓的人都不可能说谎。
Nobody who swears to God could possibly be lying.
(低沉的枪声)
[muffled gunshot]
啊!
Aaaah!
你和你的搭档偷了310万美元
You and your partner stole  $3.1 million
来自迈阿密的朋友
from our friends in Miami.
或多或少。
More or less.
他们还没有确切的数字。
They don't have  the exact figure yet.
我没有!
I don't have it!
本拿走了钱!
Ben took the money!
本·格鲁伯，你的搭档，对吧?这是正确的。
Ben Gruber, your partner, right?  That's right.
我们本该下周见面，分钱的。
We were supposed to meet up next week, split the money.
满足在哪里?
Meet where?
我不知道。本会打电话来的。
I don't know. Ben was gonna call.
他在哪里?加州。
Where is he? California.
我就知道这么多。
That's all I know.
那边的明信片。
That postcard over there.
“静观其变。
"Sit tight.
我下周给你打电话。”
I'll call next week."
我就知道这么多。
That's all I know.
我发誓。
I swear.
我有个坏消息要告诉你，鲁迪。
I got bad news for you, Rudy.
我相信你。
I believe you.
啊!(低沉的枪声)
Aaah! [muffled gunshot]
[兰迪·纽曼的拉格泰姆主题曲]
[Randy Newman ragtime theme]
外面是一片丛林
* It's a jungle out there
*到处都是混乱和混乱
* Disorder and confusion everywhere *
似乎没人在乎
* No one seems to care
哦，我喜欢
* Well, I do
嘿，这里谁负责?
* Hey, who's in charge here?
外面是一片丛林
* It's a jungle out there
我们呼吸的空气中有毒
* Poison in the very air we breathe *
*你知道你喝的水里有什么吗?＊
* You know what's in the water that you drink? *
好吧，我有，而且非常棒
* Well, I do, and it's a-ma-zing *
人们认为我疯了，因为我一直在担心
* People think I'm crazy 'cause I worry all the time *
如果你注意了，你也会担心的
* If you paid attention, you'd be worried too *
*你最好关注一下这个我们如此热爱的世界*
* You'd better pay attention or this world we love so much *
*可能会杀了你
* Might just kill you
我现在可能错了
* I could be wrong now
但是我不这么认为
* But I don't think so
因为外面是一片丛林
* 'Cause it's a jungle out there *
外面是一片丛林
* It's a jungle out there *
酿酒厂在那边。
The winery's over there.
这就是旅馆。
And this is the inn.
哦，太美了。
(Natalie)  Oh, it's so beautiful.
你每年都来吗?
You come here every year?
嗯哼。
Mm-hmm.
我做不到。
I couldn't do it.
米奇和我在巴黎度蜜月。
Mitch and I honeymooned in Paris.
我还没回来。
I still haven't been back.
我必须去。
I have to come.
我答应特鲁迪了。
I promised Trudy.
哦——哦!
Oh--ooh!
我很期待放松一下。
Well, I am so looking forward to relaxing.
你知道，看书。
You know, reading a book.
洗澡。
Taking a bath.
我可能永远不会离开那个浴缸了。
Oh, I may never leave that bathtub.
呃，等一下。
Uh, wait a minute.
让我——给你。
Let me-- Here you go.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
哦，哦，邮件。
Oh, oh, the mail.
请再说一遍?
Pardon me?
我忘了告诉凯文把信拿来。
I forgot to tell Kevin to bring in the mail.
没关系，我跟他谈过了。
That's okay, I talked to him.
也许我们该给他打个电话，以防万一。
Maybe we should call him, just to--just to be sure.
蒙先生，我已经搞定了。他在拿邮件。
Mr. Monk, I took care of it. He's bringing in the mail.
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
怎么，你不相信我?
What, you don't believe me?
我为什么要在这种事上撒谎?
Why would I lie about something like that?
让我闭嘴。
To shut me up.
蒙先生，我不是骗子。我打电话给他。
Mr. Monk, I'm not a liar. I called him.
只是为了确定。
Just to be sure.
蒙先生，我们现在是合伙人了。
Mr. Monk, we are partners now.
这意味着我们必须互相信任。
That means we have to trust each other.
这就是规则，好吗?
That is the rule, okay?
我必须相信你。你必须相信我。
I have to trust you. You have to trust me.
不管我们说什么。
No matter what we say.
你是对的。我很抱歉。
You're right. I'm sorry.
好的。
Okay.
(阿蒙)哦，不。
(Monk)  Oh, no.
哦,不。什么?
Oh, no.  What?
哦，太不一样了。
Oh, it's so different.
这跟我记忆中的完全不一样。
This is not at all the way I remember it.
感觉更好?
Feel better?
(女人)艾德里安!
(woman)  Adrian!
你好!
Hello!
欢迎回来。
Welcome back.
欢迎回家。
Uh, welcome home.
你好,西尔维娅。
Hello, Sylvia.
真的已经一年了吗?
Has it really been a year already?
哦，你一定是娜塔莉。
Oh, you must be Natalie.
欢迎来到葡萄酒之乡。
Welcome to wine country.
西尔维亚•威利斯。
Sylvia Willis.
西尔维娅敬我的朋友们，我希望是所有人。
Sylvia to my friends, whom I hope is everybody.
艾利安，我把你的房间收拾好了。
Oh, Adrian, I've got your room all ready.
你特别的枕头，特别的毛巾，
Your special pillows, special towels,
还有你特制的肥皂。
and your special soap.
希望你收到我关于地毯的信了。哦,是的。
And I hope you got my letter about the rug. Oh, yes.
他们不得不换掉其中一张地毯。
They had to replace one of the rugs.
谢谢你这么善解人意。
Oh, thank you for being so understanding.
请您签到好吗?
Uh, would you sign in, please?
你将住在204房间，在楼梯顶端。
You're going to be in room 204 at the top of the stairs.
西尔维娅，我想再次为去年的事道歉
Sylvia, I want to apologize again for last year--
哦，别客气。这是古老的历史。
Oh, don't mention it. It's ancient history.
去年发生了什么?
What happened last year?
嗯，不值一提。
Well, it's not worth mentioning.
我们有一个…神秘的周末。
We had a...mystery weekend.
我们还雇了一些演员
And we hired some actors
谁会来一场小小的谋杀
who were going to act out a little murder--
我真的，真的很抱歉。
I'm really, really sorry.
而且，本来是三天的。
And, uh, it was supposed to be for three days.
而且每个人都提前付了三天的钱。
And everybody paid in advance for three days.
艾利安在，12分钟内就破案了吗?
Adrian solved the case in-- what was it, 12 minutes?
我知道
Well, I-I knew
将军的女儿在撒谎
that the general's daughter was lying
和丘吉尔见面，
about meeting Churchill,
因为丘吉尔直到1953年才被封为爵士。
because Churchill wasn't knighted until 1953.
也就是说雷金纳德，那个瘸腿司机，
Which meant that Reginald, the limping chauffeur,
为她提供不在场证明的人，也在撒谎。
who supplied her alibi, was also lying.
很明显，他们是恋人
So obviously, they were lovers
谁在计划杀死苏丹。
who were planning to kill the sultan--
不管怎样,嗯…偷走阿拉伯祖母绿
Anyway, uh... and steal the Arabian Emerald.
我们不得不把每个人的钱都退了。
we had to refund everybody's money.
没什么大不了的。
No big deal.
但我们吸取了教训。
But we learned our lesson.
不再神秘
No more mysteries
艾德里安·蒙克来的时候
when Adrian Monk is in town.
这次我们要品酒。
This time we're having a wine tasting.
你喜欢酒吗，娜塔莉?
Uh, do you enjoy wine, Natalie?
比我应该做的多一点。
A little more than I should.
哦，那你一定要加入我们。
Oh, then you must join us.
艾利安，你不喝酒
Uh, Adrian, you don't drink,
你呢?不。
do you? No.
哦,很好。完美的。
Oh, good. Perfect.
这是你的钥匙。
Here are your keys.
你知道路。
You know the way.
如果你有什么需要，尽管打电话。
Now, if you need anything, you just call.
好的。
Okay.
娜塔莉，我要在这里坐一会儿。
Natalie, I'm going to sit down here for a little while.
这是一种传统。
It's sort of a tradition.
你想找人陪你吗?
You want some company?
不，不，我没事的。我不会孤单的。
No, no, I'll-- I'll be fine. I won't be alone.
好的。
Okay.
晚安，蒙先生。
Well, have a good night, Mr. Monk.
休息一下。
Get some rest.
我没有一天不想你。
Not a day goes by when I don't think about you.
我从没觉得跟你这么亲近过
And I-I never feel as close to you
就像我在这里一样
as I do when I'm here.
它总是——
It's always--
哦，不，不——求求你，别管它。拜托。
Oh no, no-- Please, leave it. Please.
它是1984。
It's 1984.
是的，先生，1984年的Allacco解百纳。
Yes, sir. Allacco Cabernet, 1984.
上面有你的名字。
It had your name on it.
这是我妻子的最爱。
It was my wife's favorite.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
谢谢你嫁给我。
For marrying me.
你在想什么?
What were you thinking?
我——我很抱歉。可能是我。
I--I'm sorry.  That's probably me.
我对水Velva有点热情。
I was a little enthusiastic with the Aqua Velva.
你介意我休息一下吗?
Do you mind if I rest my cheeks?
事实上，我喜欢哦，如果有人来，我就起来。
Actually, I do-- Oh, well, if someone comes, I'll get up.
我讨厌一个人喝酒。
[whispers] I hate drinking alone.
呃，麻烦你一下?
Um, por favor?
波德里亚·托玛
Uh, podria tomar
una copa de Degout Pinot?
[笑]
[chuckles]
我，我懂两种语言。
Oh, I'm--I'm, uh, bilingual.
我母亲是委内瑞拉人。
My mother was Venezuelan.
这意味着我可以让自己出丑
That means I can make an ass of myself
两种语言。(笑)
in two languages. [laughs]
哦，不好意思。对不起，对不起。
Oh, hoo hoo, excuse me. Pardon me, I'm sorry.
为了我的心。
For my heart.
我的老心脏。
My old ticker.
拉里Zwibell。
Larry Zwibell.
Adrian阿蒙。
Adrian Monk.
艾利安，很高兴认识你。
Adrian, nice to know you.
什么风把你吹来了?
So what brings you here?
你是来参加什么，品酒会的吗?
Are you here for the, uh-- what, the wine tasting?
不，我每年都来。这是一种传统。
No, I come every year. It's kind of a tradition.
哦，那太好了。
Oh, that's--that's nice.
啊,请。
Ah, please.
毫米。
Mm.
嗯,毫米毫米。毫米。
Mm, mm-mm. Mm.
哦,超验。
Oh, transcendent.
就像一顿饭。
Like a meal in itself.
哦，想想看。
Oh, just think.
一周前，我甚至买不起一瓶汽水。
A week ago, I couldn't even afford a bottle of pop.
哦,令人难以置信的。嗯。
Oh, fabulous. Hmm.
嘿，你没事吧?
Hey, are you all right?
我不太会喝酒。
I'm not much of a drinker.
哦。你喝了多少?
Oh. How many have you had?
一个瓶子吗?一个sip。
One bottle? One sip.
哦。
Oh.
好吧，如果你明天醒来还醉着，
Well, if you wake up tomorrow and you're still hammered,
你得来找我。
you gotta come find me.
我在后面楼梯旁的202房间。
I'm in room 202 by the back staircase.
我找到了很好的治疗方法
I got a great cure
对于宿醉，这是百分百保证的。
for a hangover, it's 100% guaranteed.
呃。
Uh.
所以，如果你不介意的话，我要
So, um, if you'll excuse me, I'm, uh--
我要教这些乡巴佬怎么打扑克。
I'm gonna teach these rubes how to play some poker.
(笑)很高兴认识你。
[laughs] Nice knowing you.
你好!
Hello!
你好,每个人。嗨。
Hello, everybody. Hi.
你在玩什么?
So, uh, what are you playing?
这是一个友好的小游戏。
It's a friendly little game.
我以为你在打扑克。
Oh, I thought you were playing poker.
(笑声)嘿，这个位子有人坐吗?
[laughter] Hey, is this seat taken?
来吧，坐下。谢谢你！
Go ahead, sit down.  Thank you.
我的天啊。
Oh, Mon Dieu.
抱歉，那。你知道吗?
I'm sorry, that's-- you know what?
这可能是Aqua Velva。
That's probably the Aqua Velva.
天啊，你做了什么?
Oh, my God, what'd you do?
在里面洗澡?
Take a bath in it?
不，我没有。
No, I didn't.
但这不是一个坏主意。
But that's not a bad idea.
我下次再试试。
I'll try it next time.
嘿，Larry Zwibell。
Hey, Larry Zwibell.
你好。嗨。
Hi. Hi.
我带了几个朋友来。
I brought a couple friends with me.
也许你们都想打个招呼。
Maybe you'd all like to say hi.
啊,欢迎。
Ah, bienvenue.
皮埃尔Lecoste。
Pierre Lecoste.
啊，你好，皮埃尔。
Ah, bonjour, Pierre.
卡尔·格夫斯基，你好。
Cal Gefsky, hi.
这是我妻子海蒂。
This is my wife Heidi.
海蒂。
Heidi.
的妻子。
Wife.
我只是不习惯。
I just can't get used to that.
我们周六刚结婚。
Oh, we just got married on Saturday.
(Larry)祝贺。
(Larry)  Congratulations.
大卫Sobin。
David Sobin.
很高兴见到你。
Nice to see you.
你知道，他是个精神病医生。所以要小心他。
He's a psychiatrist, you know. So watch out for him.
一个缩水吗?不，你在开玩笑，等等，等等。
A shrink? No, you're kidding--wait, hold on.
我有一个很棒的笑话。好的。你们听过这个吗?
I got a great joke. Okay. Have you guys heard this one?
一个人去看心理医生
A guy goes to a psychiatrist
他说，“医生，
and he says, "Doctor,
我妻子认为她是一台冰箱。”
my wife thinks  she's a refrigerator."
精神病医生说:“好吧，别理她。”
And the psychiatrist says,  "Well, just ignore her."
那个人说，
And the guy says,
“我不能。
"I can't.
“当她张着嘴睡觉的时候，小光
"When she sleeps with her mouth open, the little light
让我整晚都睡不着。”
keeps me awake all night."
(笑声)
[laughter]
艾利安，怎么，你打算放弃吗?
Hey, Adrian, what, are you gonna give up?
我想是的。晚安，各位。
I think so. Good night.
哦，你说什么?
Oh, excuse me?
你说什么?
Um, excuse me?
你走之前，能帮我们拍张照吗?
Um, before you go, would you take our picture?
哦，这是个好主意。
Oh, that's a good idea.
静静不动。
Hold still.
——不要动。
Hold--hold still.
准备好了…
Ready...
微笑。
Smile.
等等，我们从老到小。
Wait, let--let's stand oldest to youngest.
那就是你，然后是你，然后是你，然后你
So that would be you, then you, then you, then you--
阿蒙先生。
Mr. Monk.
我来拍这张照片。
I will take the picture.
哦，蒙先生。我只是来接你的。
Oh, Mr. Monk. I was just coming to get you.
嘘。今天天气很好。
Shh.  It's a beautiful day.
楼下有一顿美味的早餐。嘘!
They have an amazing breakfast downstairs. Shh!
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
(叹息)
[groans]
你喝酒了吗?
Were you drinking?
只是…一点。
Just...a little.
连一杯都没有。
Not even a glass.
(叹息)
[groans]
我认识了一个人。
Oh--oh, I met a guy.
他住202号房。
He's in 202.
他说他有治疗方法。
He said he had a cure for this.
他说，他说这是有保证的。
Uh, he said it was-- he said it was guaranteed.
哦,在这里。202.
Oh, here. 202.
202.
拉里?我是昨晚的艾利安。
Larry? It's-- it's Adrian from last night.
喂?
Hello?
哦，对不起。我在找拉里。
Oh, I'm sorry. I-I was looking for Larry.
你换房间了吗?
Uh, did you switch rooms?
不，不，不。
No, no, no.
他说是202。
Well, he said 202.
在后面。
At the back.
你在说谁?
Wh-wh-who are you talking about?
拉里……
Larry...
拉里Zwibell。
Larry Zwibell.
昨晚的。
Uh, from last night.
你和他打扑克?
You played poker with him?
不，不。你错了。
Uh, no, no. You're mistaken.
你看，我不认识叫这个名字的人。
You see, I don't know anybody by this name.
哦，早上好。
Oh, good morning.
我希望你饿了。
I hope you're hungry.
嗨，早上好。
Hi, good morning.
我们在找客人。Larry Zwibell。
We're looking for a guest. A Larry Zwibell.
谁?
Who?
他昨晚入住了。你还记得吗?202房间。
He checked in last night. You remember? Room 202.
艾利安，昨天没人登记入住
Adrian, nobody checked in yesterday
除了你和娜塔莉
except for you and Natalie.
不。不，不，不。西尔维娅。
No. No, no, no. Sylvia.
我跟他谈过了。
I talked to him.
H-he——拉里Zwibell。
H-he--Larry Zwibell.
你自己看吧。
See for yourself.
他在这里。我跟他谈过了。
He was here. I talked to him.
你必须相信我。
You have to believe me.
好的。
Okay.
停车场里有三辆车，加上我的。
There are three cars in the parking lot, plus mine.
和昨晚停在那里的三辆车一样。
The same three cars that were there last night.
也许他离开了。
Maybe he left.
但这不能解释为什么大家都在说谎。
But that wouldn't explain why everybody's lying.
那他为什么不去报到?他没有登记入住。
Then why didn't he check in? He di check in.
他说是202房间。
He said room 202.
看。
Look.
我们在这一页的底部签了名。
We signed in on the bottom of this page.
她本可以删掉下一页的。
She could've removed the next page.
她为什么要这么做，蒙先生?
Why would she do that, Mr. Monk?
我不知道。
I don't know.
发生了一件事。
Something happened.
这里发生了一些事情。
Something happened here.
来吧。
Come on.
你确定你只喝了一杯吗?
Are you sure you only had one drink?
娜塔莉，我见过他。
Natalie, I met him.
他会说西班牙语。
He--he spoke Spanish.
他身上散发着水Velva的味道。
And he reeked of Aqua Velva.
你相信我，对吧?
You believe me, right?
你说过我们要相信彼此。
You said we have to believe each other.
你说这是规则。
You said that was the rule.
这是真的。
That's true.
(清了清喉咙)
[clears throat]
不好意思，打扰你们了。
Excuse me, I'm sorry to bother you all.
但我们在找客人。拉里Zwibell。
But we're looking for a guest. Larry Zwibell.
他昨晚在这儿。谁?
He was here last night. Who?
我说过我没听说过他。
I told you I never heard of him.
他和你一起打扑克。
He played poker with you.
他跟你讲了那个心理医生的笑话。
He told you that joke about the psychiatrist.
觉得自己是冰箱的妻子。
The wife who thinks  she's a refrigerator.
精神科医生说"别理它"
And the psychiatrist says, "Just ignore it."
但是男人说:“我不能，因为当她睡觉的时候
But the man says, "I can't because when she sleeps
“她张着嘴，
"with her mouth open,
她嘴里的小光让我睡不着。”
the little light inside her mouth keeps me awake."
(笑声)太棒了。
[laughter] That's brilliant.
你笑什么?
Why are you laughing?
因为这很有趣。
Because it's funny.
但你已经听过了。
B-b-but you already heard it.
你昨晚也听到了。
You heard it last night.
他们已经听到了。
They already heard it.
也许是你送货的问题。
Maybe it's your delivery.
你注意到那个法国人这样做了吗?
Did you notice the French guy did this?
他就是这么说的。
That's his tell.
昨晚我在看他打扑克。
I was watching him play poker last night.
每当他虚张声势时，他就揉鼻子。
Whenever he bluffed, he rubbed his nose.
我跟你说，他之前也在楼上干过。
I'm telling you, he did it upstairs earlier too.
他是在撒谎。他们都在撒谎。
He's lying. They are all lying.
这是个阴谋。
It's--it's a conspiracy.
蒙先生，为什么?
Mr. Monk, why?
他们甚至不认识对方。
They don't even know each other.
啊。
Ah.
里卡多。先生吗?
Ricardo. Señor?
里卡多。
Ricardo.
里卡多，你还记得我的朋友吧。
Ricardo, you remember my friend.
他，他当时和我一起坐在那张桌子上。
He was--he was sitting with me at that table right there.
他跟你说西班牙语。
He spoke Spanish to you.
他点了Degout Pinot。
He ordered the Degout Pinot.
对不起，Señor。那里一个人也没有。
I am sorry, Señor. There was no one there.
你一整晚都是一个人。
You were alone all night.
里卡多打扰一下。
Ricardo-- Excuse me.
你起得真早啊。
Well, you're getting an early start.
试吃要中午才开始。
The tasting doesn't begin until noon.
我可以吗?确定。
May I? Sure.
哦，他们在这里做这个。毫米。
Oh, they make this here. Mm.
他们今早才发布的。
They just released it this morning.
它是怎样的?
And how is it?
很好。这…这很甜蜜。
It's good. It's, uh-- It's sweet.
但是它有一个
But it has a, um--
它有一种奇怪的余味。
It has a weird aftertaste to it.
你尝过了吗?
Do you taste it?
不，不完全是。
No, not really.
我有点担心你的朋友。
I'm a little bit worried about your friend.
我是心理医生，我昨天见过他
I'm a psychiatrist, and I saw him yesterday
对着空椅子说话。
talking to an empty chair.
哦，是的，他就是这么做的。
Oh, yeah, he does that.
他的妻子八年前去世了。他和她说话。
His wife died eight years ago. He talks to her.
威利斯太太说他以前是个侦探。
Mrs. Willis said he used to be a detective.
他出院了?
He was discharged?
我能问一下，他为什么在这里吗?
May I ask, why is he here?
今天是他的周年纪念日，他们在这里度蜜月，所以。
Well, it's his anniversary, and they honeymooned here, so.
所以。
So.
这可能是他压力很大的时候。
This is probably a time of stress for him.
他能很好地处理压力吗?
Does he handle stress well?
不。他不能很好地处理压力。
No. He handles stress unwell.
孤独的孩子有时会在心里编造一个人。
Lonely children will sometimes make up a person in their minds.
一个想象中的朋友，如果你愿意的话。
An imaginary friend, if you will.
我在实践中见过很多次。
I've seen it a lot in my practice.
我也见过成年人这么做。
I've seen adults do it too.
你不了解艾德里安·蒙克。
Well, you don't know Adrian Monk.
他是个伟大的侦探。
He's a great detective.
警察没有和他谈过是不会采取行动的。
The police don't make a move without talking to him first.
我不知道这是怎么回事。
I don't know what's going on here.
但如果他说他见过一个叫拉里·兹维贝尔的人，
But if he says he met a man named Larry Zwibell,
然后他遇到了一个叫拉里·兹维贝尔的人。
then he met a man named Larry Zwibell.
哦。这很有趣。
Oh. This is interesting.
楼上什么都没有。
There's nothing upstairs.
这是怎么呢
What's going on?
嗯…原谅我。
Um...excuse me.
娜塔莉:你怎么看?
(Natalie)  What do you think?
关于什么?
About what?
签名。
The signature.
画家。
The painter.
他的名字和……
He has the same name as...
是我的幻觉?
As my hallucination?
嘿，我可没那么说。
Hey, I didn't say that.
蒙先生，你得承认
Now, Mr. Monk, you gotta admit,
看起来有点糟糕。
it looks kinda bad.
人们可能会认为你…
People might think that you...
看到这个名字…
saw the name and...
编了一个人。
made up a person.
或者是我遇到的那个男人
Or the man I met
看到画上的名字了
saw the name on that painting
然后决定为自己所用。
and decided to use it for himself.
相机。
The camera.
娜塔莉，他们昨晚拍了张照片。
Natalie, they took a photo last night.
合影。
A-a-a group photo.
他就在里面。
And he was in it.
这是我们2002年的赤霞珠。
And this is our 2002 Cabernet Sauvignon.
我想你会喜欢的。
I think you'll like it.
它比梅洛(Merlot)更柔和，单宁含量更高。
It's slightly softer and more tannic than the Merlot.
你一定要拿到那个相机。
You've got to get that camera.
你待在这里。
You stay here.
你会加入我们吗?
Ah, will you  be joining us?
是的。好。
Yes. Good.
人越多越好。谢谢你！
The more the merrier. Thank you.
接下来，我们要尝尝西拉酒。
Next, we're going to try the Syrah.
现在，西拉是用我们自己的葡萄酿造的
Now, the Syrah comes from our very own grapes
在东边的葡萄园。
in the east vineyard.
你在喝什么?
What are you drinking?
呃，是Sierra Springs。
Uh, it's the, uh, the Sierra Springs.
怎么样?
How is it?
它是精致的。
It's exquisite.
这是……第一次品酒?
Is this... your first wine tasting?
我会解释他们在做什么。
I'll explain what they're doing.
有五个步骤。我们称它们为五个s。
There are five steps. We call them the five Ss.
看，旋，闻，抿，吐。
See, swirl, sniff, sip, and spit.
现在，他们正处于第一步。这酒看起来怎么样?
Now, they're on step one. How does the wine look?
它颜色丰富吗?它会和光发生反应吗?
Is it rich in color? Does it react with the light?
不好意思，最后一个是什么?
Excuse me--uh, what was that last one?
第五步。
Uh, step five.
随地吐痰。
Spit.
所以，他们要吐痰了?
So, th-th-they're going to be...spitting?
就是这样。
That's it.
我可以帮你拿着相机。
Mmm, I can hold your camera for you.
哦，我很好。
Oh, I'm good.
现在他们到了第三步。
Now they're  on step three.
哦，第三步。
Oh, step three.
嗅探。你闻到了酒的味道。
Sniffing. You smell the wine.
深深地吸气。
Inhale deeply.
你闻到水果味还是香草味了?
Do you smell the fruit or the herbs?
也就是说，真的，只剩下两步了
Uh, so that means, really, there's only two steps left
直到……吐痰。
until the...spitting.
这是正确的。
That's right.
一次就全部搞定?
Uh, all--all at once?
他们都在走廊上吐痰吗?
All of them spitting on the porch here?
和我在门廊上?
With me on the porch?
现在他们正在啜饮。
Now they're sipping.
喝? !
Sipping?!
所以吐痰是下一个。哦,上帝。
So spitting is next. Oh, God.
哦，它来了。
Oh, here it comes.
哦!
Ohh!
(阿蒙)啊!
(Monk)  Aah!
(笑声)
[laughter]
这真是太有趣了，不是吗?
This is so much fun, isn't it?
来张集体照怎么样?新婚夫妇的合影。
How about a group shot? A little newlywed group shot.
我买了。哦，也许以后吧。
I'll take it. Oh, maybe later.
我的天啊。
Oh, my God.
这是一种吻蕨。
It's a kissing fern.
一个什么?
A what?
是的。它们叫做吻蕨。
Yeah. They're called kissing ferns.
这对新婚夫妇来说应该是好运
It's supposed to be good luck for newlyweds
在其中亲吻。
to kiss underneath one.
你没听过那首歌吗?
Haven't you heard that song?
在吻蕨下吻我，宝贝
* Kiss me under the kissing fern, baby *
蕨类植物……是的，是的，好的，是的。
Fern...yeah, yeah, okay, yeah.
好吧，既然这样，呃…
Yeah, okay, well, in that case, uh...
[娜塔莉清了清嗓子]
[Natalie clears throat]
是的。
Yeah.
在这里吗?准备好了吗?
Here? Ready?
哦,哇。你不明白。
Oh, wow. You don't get it.
太可爱了。让我拍张照片。
It's so cute. Let me take a picture.
要找个好角度。
Gotta get a great angle here.
你可以…拍张照片。
You can... take the picture.
吻我
* Kiss me
*在吻蕨下面
* Underneath the kissin' fern
*宝贝
* Baby
*悬挂式植物
* The hanging plant
*嘣嘣嘣
* Ba boom boom boom
*爱*粑粑粑粑嘣
* Of love  * Ba ba ba ba boom
接吻……
* The kissing...
你回家后会感觉好点的。
You'll feel better when you get home.
我们会打电话给克罗格医生。
We'll call Dr. Kroger.
这是星期六。
It's Saturday.
我们会打电话给克罗格医生。
We'll call Dr. Kroger.
娜塔莉，我见过他。
Natalie, I met him.
我跟他谈过了。
I talked to him.
他是如此真实。
He was so real.
我怎么能，我怎么能错得这么离谱?
How could I-- How could I be so wrong?
我这辈子都不会再喝酒了。
I'm never taking another drink as long as I live.
蒙先生，有些人就是没有忍耐力。
Mr. Monk, some people just have no tolerance.
我以前在酒吧工作。我一直都在看。
I used to work in a bar. I saw it all the time.
你只喝了两口。
You had two sips.
对一个正常人来说就相当于10枪。
That's like 10 shots to a normal person.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
嘿，伙计们，你们好吗?
Hey, folks, how you doing?
听着，我在找我弟弟。
Listen, I'm looking for my brother.
他失踪了。
He's gone missing.
你见过他吗?
Have you seen him?
这是他!
That's him!
就是他!你认识他吗?
That's the guy! You know him?
我昨晚见过他!
I-I met him last night!
真的吗?
Really?
这是他!
That's him!
想跟我说说吗?
Wanna tell me about it?
我不知道他跟你说了什么。
I don't know what  he told you, you know.
他的真名叫本·格鲁伯。
His real name is Ben Gruber.
我们的母亲非常担心他。
Our mother's been worried sick about him.
感谢上帝!
Thank God!
我以为我疯了。
I thought I was losing my mind.
我知道他喜欢酒
I knew he was into wine,
所以我查了所有的葡萄园
so I've been checking all the vineyards
还有附近的小旅馆。
and the little hotels in the area.
你是他哥哥?
And you're his brother?
艾伦，艾伦·格鲁伯。快乐。
Allen, Allen Gruber. Pleasure.
嗨，娜塔莉·缇哲。
Hi, Natalie Teeger.
我是艾德里安·蒙克。
This is Adrian Monk.
让我把话说清楚。
Let me  get this straight.
这里的每个人都假装从没见过他?
Everybody here is pretending they never met him?
每一个人。
Everyone.
哦……可怜的孩子。
Ohh...poor kid.
他肯定被吓死了
He's gotta be scared to death.
为什么?
Why?
他偷了一些钱。
He stole some money.
来自他工作的银行，对吗?
From a bank that he works for, right?
然后他就走了。
And he took off.
我跟地方检察官谈过，她说，
I talked to the local D.A. and she said, you know,
如果他自首，他们会对他从轻发落。
they'd go easy on him if he turned himself in.
我就是为此而来的。
That's why I'm here.
我想，如果我去了，
I figured, you know, if I showed up,
也许我能找到他。
maybe I could find him.
也许我能说服他把钱还回去。
Maybe I could talk him into returning the money.
他拿走了多少?
How much did he take?
310万美元。
$3.1 million.
唷。唷!
Whew. Whew!
不过听起来他已经花了一部分了。
Although it sounds like he's spending some of it already.
他一直在收买别人
He's been paying people off
说他们从没听说过他。
to say they've never heard of him.
你觉得他还在这里吗?
(Natalie)  You think he's still here?
我是说，他为什么要留下?
I mean, why would he stay?
他开的什么车?
What was he driving?
86年的别克。
'86 Buick, last I heard.
几率有多大?
What are the odds?
一辆86年的别克。
An '86 Buick.
不可能是他的。
Well, it can't be his.
这辆车一直在这里。
This car has been here forever.
嗯，我不这么认为。
Mmm, I don't think so.
这里有个凹痕，但没有生锈。
There's a dent here, but no rust.
轮孔里也没有生锈。
And there's no rust in the wheel wells.
这辆车来的时间不长。
This car hasn't been here long.
所以他还在这附近。
So he's still here somewhere.
他不在那栋房子里。
Well, he's not in that house.
我们称之为桶房。
And we call this the barrel room.
这些容器装满了60加仑
These containers are filled with 60 gallons
我们举世闻名的霞多丽酒。
of our world-famous Chardonnay.
它会在这些容器中老化
It's going to age in these containers
整整11个月。
for exactly 11 months.
我喜欢把它看作是有生命的东西。
I like to think of it as a living thing.
就像一个婴儿在母亲的子宫里生长。
Like a baby growing inside a mother's womb.
格鲁伯先生!
Mr. Gruber!
我以为我们失去你了。
I thought we'd lost you.
哦,对不起。我只是回头了。
Oh, sorry. I just got turned around.
如果你跟着我，我们真的会
If you follow me, we're literally going to be
时光倒流。
stepping back in time.
踩酒，这是传统
Wine stomping-- it's a tradition
这要追溯到几千年前
that goes back thousands of years
希腊人。
to the Greeks.
我们是加州仅存的几个葡萄园之一
We're one of the last vineyards in California
至少他们的一些葡萄酒是用这种方法酿造的。
that at least makes some of their wine using this method.
哦，我的天啊。
(Monk)  Oh, my God.
人们真的会喝吗?
Do people actually drink that?
是的，我想是的。
Yeah, I think so.
他们疯了吗?
Are they insane?
去问问她他们是不是疯了。
Go, ask her if they're insane.
问问她就知道了。
Just ask her.
我不会问她的，蒙先生。
I'm not gonna ask her that, Mr. Monk.
当然我们不能把所有的酒都压成这样。
And of course we can't press all of our wine like this.
那太花时间了。
It would take too long.
但我们确实用这种方法做了一个标签。
But we do make one label using this method.
Allacco解百纳。啊!
The Allacco Cabernet. Aah!
可以在我们门口的商店买到。
It can be bought from our store out front.
赤霞珠。
Cabernet.
这酒我喝了15年了。
I've been drinking that wine for 15 years.
这是脚酒!
It's foot wine!
我能尝出来。
I can taste it.
噢,来吧!你尝不出来。
Oh...come on! You cannot taste it.
I-I-I即可。我现在都能尝到脚的味道了。
I-I-I can. I can taste the feet now.
我能尝到，还有脚趾。
I can taste-- and the toes.
还有脚趾之间的部分。
And what's between the toes.
还有真菌。
And the fungus.
这真的很野蛮。
It really is barbaric.
好吧，我没看到真菌。
Okay, I didn't see any fungus.
我相信他们的脚一定很干净。
Look, I'm sure they have clean feet.
这种事可能是有规定的。
There are probably rules about that stuff.
好吧，我承认。太恶心了。
Okay, I admit it. That's pretty disgusting.
看到后面有个自动售货机。
Saw a vending machine back there.
你要苏打水吗?
You want a soda?
原谅我吗?
Excuse me?
把你的嘴洗干净。你要苏打水吗?
To wash your mouth out. You want a soda?
那太好了。谢谢。
That would be great. Thanks.
我很幸运。
Tome su tiempo.
什么?
What?
意思是，“慢慢来。”
It means, "Take your time."
正确的。
Right.
(低语)娜塔莉。
[whispering] Natalie.
娜塔莉，他在撒谎。
Natalie, he's lying.
这个人和我昨晚遇到的那个人
This guy and the man I met last night
我们不是兄弟。
are not brothers.
他只说了“苏打水”。
He just said "soda."
还有兹威贝尔，格鲁伯，不管他叫什么
And Zwibell, Gruber, or whatever his name is
说“流行”。
said "pop."
他会两种语言。
And he was bilingual.
这家伙一句西班牙语都不会说。
This guy doesn't speak a word of Spanish.
他们不可能在同一所房子里长大。
They could not have grown up in the same house.
好吧，我得弄清楚他到底是谁。
Okay, I need to find out who he really is.
听……你能撬开他的车吗?
Listen...can you break into his car?
我能撬开他的车吗?
Can I break into his car?
是的，我会。好的。
Yes, I can. Okay.
我会让他忙起来的。我带他去酒吧。
I'll keep him busy. I'll take him to the bar.
试着把他灌醉。让他放松。
Try to get him drunk. Loosen him up.
也许他会犯错误。
Maybe he'll make a misstep.
等等，等等，等等。你要喝酒?
Wait, wait, wait. You're gonna drink?
别担心。我知道我在做什么。
Don't worry. I know what I'm doing.
嗨。
Hi.
我和我朋友坐在那边。
I'm sitting with my friend over there.
他想要一瓶你们家的白葡萄酒。
He would like a bottle of your house white.
好的。
Okay.
还有，你们有无酒精的葡萄酒吗?
And, uh, do you have any non-alcoholic wine?
我们有非常好的红葡萄酒。零酒精。
We have a very nice Claret. Zero alcohol.
一点酒都没有
No alcohol at all.
我就是这么说的。
That's what I said.
我要那个。
I'll have that.
你能把它放在玻璃瓶里吗?
Could you put it in a carafe?
啊哈。你不用带瓶子。
Uh-huh. You don't have to bring the bottle.
你说对了。我们会拿给您的。
You got it. We'll bring it over to you.
(硬币叮当声)
[coin clinks]
12号桌要一瓶精选白葡萄酒。
Table twelve needs a bottle of the house white.
再来一瓶波尔多红酒。
And a carafe of that Claret.
你说对了。
You got it.
给你。
Here you go.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
我真的很感激你……这么感兴趣…
I do appreciate you... taking such an interest...
阿蒙先生。
Mr. Monk.
好吧，我也有个哥哥。
Oh, well, I have a brother too.
我会担心死的
I'd be worried sick
如果他出了什么事。
if anything happened to him.
所以…敬你哥哥。
So...to your brother.
不管他在哪里。
Wherever the hell he is.
口渴的男孩。
Thirsty boy.
有本事就来抓我。
Catch me if you can.
你有很多朋友吗?
Do you have  a lot of friends?
我敢打赌你会的。
I'll bet you do.
有时我…
Sometimes I...
打开电视。
turn on the TV.
然后我把声音调小…
And I turn the sound way down...
和…我假装他们在跟我说话。
And...I pretend that they're talking to me.
每个人都喜欢我。
And everybody likes me.
”阿德里安。欢迎回来。
"Adrian. Welcome back.
“哦，我们很高兴见到你。
"Oh, we're so happy to see you.
我们很高兴见到你。”
We are so happy to see you."
我打赌你有很多朋友。
I'll bet you have a lot of friends.
你看起来像驼鹿。
You look like a moose.
(笑)你有。
[laughs] You do.
我会给你打电话的
I'm gonna call you
像麋鹿一样的卢克先生。
Mr. Luke Like-a-Moose.
(笑)Luke like a moose。
[laughing] Luke Like-a-Moose.
那么，关于你哥哥…
So, about your brother...
驼鹿的事我很抱歉…
I'm sorry about the moose thing...
嘿!
Hey!
(银器卡嗒卡嗒响)
[silverware clattering]
这是什么歌?
What song is this?
(吹口哨)
[whistling]
史托图梅耶上尉，拜托。这很重要。
Captain Stottlemeyer, please. It's important.
也许你已经受够了，蒙先生。
Maybe you've had enough, Mr. Monk.
不。不，不，不。
No. No, no, no, no.
嗯…我很好。
Um...I'm fine.
我很好。(叹息)
I'm fine. [groans]
这不是很棒吗?
Isn't this great?
只是几个人坐在旋转餐厅里。
Just a couple of guys sitting in a revolving restaurant.
啊，我喜欢。
Ah, I love that.
嘿,上气不接下气。
[breathless] Hey.
蒙先生，我能跟你谈谈吗
Mr. Monk, could I just talk to you for a second
在私人吗?
in private?
[娜塔莉假装笑]
[Natalie feigning laughter]
就是这样。
That's it.
[蒙克歇斯底里地笑]
[Monk laughing hysterically]
加油，加油，加油，加油。
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
(笑)来吧。
[laughing] Come on.
你喝醉了!
You're drunk!
(笑)不，它不含酒精。
[laughing] No, it's non-alcoholic.
(阿蒙笑)
[Monk laughing]
他就在我想要的地方!
I got him right where I want him!
看！我眨眼。
Look! I'm winking.
蒙先生，听我说!
Okay, Mr. Monk, listen to me!
你说得对，他不叫格鲁伯。
You were right-- his name isn't Gruber.
我是小艾尔·尼科莱托。
It's Al Nicoletto, Jr.
他被逮捕过五次，没有被定罪。
He has five arrests, no convictions.
听着，他是个职业杀手。
Look, he's a contract killer.
艾尔，这是真的吗?
Al, is this true?
是或不是，这是真的吗?
Yes or no, is this true?
我已经报警了!
(Natalie) I already called the police!
他们在路上了，别做傻事。
They're on their way, so don't do anything stupid.
(尼科莱托)别做傻事。
(Nicoletto) Don't you do anything stupid.
所以大家都同意了!
And so it is agreed!
让这句话传出去
And let the word go forth
没有人会做傻事。
that nobody will do anything stupid.
走吧，走吧。你在做什么?
Let's go, let's go. What are you doing?
哦，你以后会感谢我的。
Oh, you'll thank me later.
忘掉瓶子吧!
Forget the bottle!
啊!
Ahh!
主要研究!
Unh!
啊!蒙先生，打他!
Uhh! Mr. Monk, hit him!
与什么?
With what?
啊!瓶子!
Aah! The bottle!
哪一个?
Which one?
(咕哝着)没关系!
[grunting] It doesn't matter!
(普通员工)
[grunts]
我的天啊。
Oh, my God.
我差点心脏病发作。
I almost had a heart attack.
哦,上帝。
Oh, God.
心脏病发作。
Heart attack.
是的，我得说他很重要。
(Stottlemeyer)  Yeah, I'd say he's  pretty important.
联调局派了一架私人飞机去接他。
The feds are sending  a private plane to pick him up.
这是9毫米。
It's 9mm.
本·格鲁伯的搭档被发现中枪身亡
Ben Gruber's partner was found shot to death
在纽约的酒店房间里
in his hotel room in New York City
五天前。
five days ago.
我打赌这些子弹和这把枪吻合。
Now, I'm betting that those bullets match this gun.
他们抓住他了。
They got him.
看着联调局把功劳都占了。
Watch the feds take all the credit.
队长……
Captain...
你得看看这个。
You have got to see this.
蒙克在里面做加法呢。
Monk's in there doing one of his summation things.
他浪费了。
He's wasted.
当我听到…当我听到…
When I hear--when I heard N-n-nat'lie...
比如说她差点心脏病发作…
say she almost had a heart attack...
我记得——我记得
I remember--  I remembered...that
拉里•Zwibell
Larry Zwibell,
也就是本·格鲁伯
a.k.a. also known as  Ben Gruber,
(耳语)正在吃心脏药。
[whispering] was taking heart medicine.
如帽般的!
Cappy!
女士们，先生们，
Ladies and gentlemen,
利兰·斯托特梅尔上尉。
Captain Leland Stottlemeyer.
杀人!
Homicide!
给他们看看你的警徽。
Show--show 'em your badge.
表现出来。给他们看看——给他们看看。
Show it. Show 'em--show--show it.
表现出来。阿蒙,
Show it. Monk--
我破了这个案子。
I solved the case.
很好。好，好，好。
Good. Good, good, good.
让我们,嗯……
Let's--let's, um...
让这些人回房间去，好吗?
Let's let these people go up to their rooms, okay?
你的枪呢?
Where's your gun?
他有枪。
He's got a gun.
好的。哦,不!不，不，不，不!
Okay. Oh, no! No, no, no, no!
蒙克:不，不，不。你不明白。
Monk-- No, no, no. You don't understand.
不，不，不。这些就是嫌疑犯!
No, no, no.  These are the suspects!
哦,是的。
Oh, yeah.
他们都参与其中。
They're all in on it.
(施托图梅尔)那么，他们做了什么?
(Stottlemeyer) Well, what did they do?
嗯，他们——看看他们!
Well, they-- Look at them!
我的意思是，看!
I mean, look!
哦，看看他们!好的。好的。
Oh, look at 'em! Okay. Okay.
他们可能看起来不像冷血杀手，
They may not look like cold-blooded killers,
但是他们，呃…哦……
but they're, uh... ooh...
嘿，他们是罪犯。
Heh, they're crinimals.
是的。
Yeah.
他们是小偷。
They're crinimals.
刑事。
Crinimal.
(仔细)罪犯。
[carefully] Criminals.
蒙先生!
[gasps] Mr. Monk!
他们是罪犯，我告诉你!
They're criminals,  I'm telling ya!
哦,是的。
Oh, yeah.
我们需要一辆大囚车。
We're gonna need a big 'ol paddy wagon.
他们还有…水稻马车?
Do they still have... paddy wagons?
给你，蒙先生。
(Natalie)  Here you go, Mr. Monk.
请，请喝这杯咖啡。
Please, please  drink this coffee.
好的。
Okay.
小心些而已。
Be careful.
Oookay。
Oookay.
一杯咖啡。
Cup o' Joe.
好了。
There we go.
N-n-no。
N-n-no.
事情是这样的。
Here's what happened.
我十点左右上床睡觉。
I went to bed around 10:00.
他们还在打扑克。
They were still playing poker.
古柏肯定需要更多的钱
Guber must have needed more cash,
于是他上楼去拿。
so he went upstairs to get it.
我十点左右上床睡觉。
I went to bed around 10:00.
他们都还在玩扑克。
They were all still playing the poker.
(Stottlemeyer)阿蒙!
(Stottlemeyer)  Monk!
这部分我们已经听过了。
We've heard this part already.
如帽般的!卡皮，你成功了。
Cappy! Cappy, you made it.
哦…哦…
Ohh...ohh...
你好吗?
How you doing?
我…我…
I...I...
我爱你。
I love you.
我只是…
I just...
(紧张地笑)
[laughing nervously]
我也爱你，阿蒙。
I love you too, Monk.
你只是…你只是…
You just-- you just got...
你……
You...
我们去睡一觉吧。
Let's go sleep it off.
谢谢，谢谢，谢谢你…
And thank--thank-- thanks for the...
谢谢你…
thanks for the...
看看那个。
Look at that.
那是什么东西?
What's that thing?
[笑]
[chuckles]
好了，过来。过来一下。
All right, come here. Come here a minute.
我要给自己买一个。上床睡觉。
I'm gonna get me one. Up to bed.
他——!
Well, he--!
他再也没回来。
Well, he never  came back.
他们很担心，决定上楼去
They got worried and decided  to go upstairs
去看看他!
and check on him!
他们发现本·格鲁伯死了。
And they found  Ben Gruber...dead.
他死于…心脏病发作。
He was dead from a...  heart attack.
还有现金，310万美元。
And cash--  $3.1 million.
他们认为会有人来找它。
They figured somebody would be  coming around looking for it.
这就是人们想要的钱。
That's the kind of money  people come looking for.
怎么办呢?怎么办呢?
What to do?  What to do?
他们决定把尸体藏起来
They decided  to hide the body
把钱分了!
and split the money!
如果有人问起，他们就会假装
If anybody asked,  they were going to pretend
他们从未听说过他。
they never heard of him.
等一等。
Hold on.
啊。(嗅探)
Uhh. [sniffs]
事情是这样的。
Here's what happened.
他们处理掉了格鲁伯的车。
They got rid  of Gruber's car.
他们去掉了他的签名
They removed his signature
来自留言簿
from the guest book
然后在没有他的情况下重新拍了一张合影。
and retook  the group photo without him.
他走了。
He was gone.
就像他从未存在过一样。
It was like  he never existed.
像幽灵一样消失了。
Gone like a ghost.
你找到钱了吗?
Did you find the money?
还没有。
Not yet.
他说这是一个阴谋
He says there was  a conspiracy,
我们都拿了钱。
and we all took the money.
我说格鲁伯这个人把自己的车扔了，
I say this character Gruber junked his own car,
拿走了现金，
took the cash,
搭便车去了墨西哥
and hitchhiked to Mexico.
你能证明我是错的吗?
Can you prove I'm wrong?
没有。他是对的。
Nope. He's right.
没有尸体，我们就没法立案。
Without a body, we don't have a case.
阿蒙……
Monk...
(轻声打鼾)
[snoring softly]
阿蒙!
Monk!
(叹息)
[sighs]
好吧,嗯……
Okay, um...
我想你们都可以走了。
I guess you're all free to go.
中尉，记下所有人的地址。
Lieutenant, take everybody's address.
确保证件有效
Make sure it's a valid I.D.
是的,先生。
Yes, sir.
请大家跟我来。
If everybody can just follow me.
很抱歉给您带来不便。
We're sorry about  the inconvenience.
天啊，这是什么?
God, what is it?
什么是什么?
What is what?
这是他们的新酒。
This is  their new wine.
他们在隔壁装瓶。
They bottle it  next door.
但是它有这个…怪异的回味，
But it has this... funky, weird aftertaste,
我也说不清是什么原因
and I cannot put my finger on it.
在这里。
Here.
(嗅探)
[sniffs]
闻起来像水Velva。
Smells like Aqua Velva.
我的天啊。
Oh, my God.
哦，天哪!
Oh, my God!
这是Aqua Velva。
It's Aqua Velva.
(皮埃尔)这是你夫人的主意!
(Pierre) It was your lady's idea!
这不是我的主意!
It wasn't my idea!
不,不!打电话给法国领事馆!
No, no! Call the French Consulate!
不,不!
No, no!
嗯，他是个真正的派对动物。
(Stottlemeyer) Well, he's a real party animal.
[笑]
[chuckles]
好吧……
Okay...
小心驾驶，娜塔莉。
You drive safely, Natalie.
我们在校园里见。
We'll see you around campus.
好的，谢谢你，上尉。我会的。
Okay, thank you, Captain. I will.
周年快乐，艾德里安。
Happy Anniversary, Adrian.
对不起，我不相信你。
Sorry I didn't believe you.
(发动机启动)
[engine starts]